Finding Aid for the Harold Garfinkel Papers LSC.1273
UCLA Library Special Collections
- "Eliza.", 1968 April (Box 156)
  Transcripts.
- American Sociological Association (ASA). Ethnomethodology Session., 1988; 3 folders (Box 156)
  Papers submitted for presentation at the ASA 1989 Ethnomethodology Session.
- Baccus, Melinda and Harold Garfinkel., no date (Box 156)
  Transcript.
- Davis, Sherry and Harold Garfinkel., 1974 November - 1975 March; no date; 3 folders (Box 156)
  Ten (10) unedited transcripts.
- Girton, George and Harold Garfinkel., 1974 November; 1975 January (Box 156)
- Korn, Bill and Couch., 1969 February (Box 156)
- Pepinsky, Harold. Conference on human information processing (Ohio State University)., 1967 November 10 (Box 156)
  Transcript of Garfinkel's remarks.
- Publications, speeches, presentations., 1950-1989; .5 linear ft. (Box 156)
  Publications, speeches, and presentations by Harold Garfinkel; arranged chronologically.
- Sociology 148. Normal Environments., 1968 Fall (Box 156)
- Sociology 218A. Ethnomethodological Methods., 1968 Fall (Box 156)
- Sociology 251. Topics in the Problems of Social Order., 1973 Spring; 3 folders (Box 156)
- U.S. Air Force. Behavioral Science Division. Decision making and practical action grant., 1969-1970 (Box 156)
  SEE ALSO box 9: Air Force Office of Scientific Research (1961).
- UCLA Sociology students and Harold Garfinkel., no date (Box 156)
  Unedited transcript.
- Wikler, Lynn and Harold Garfinkel., 1975 April (Box 156)
  Unedited transcripts.
- Air Force Office of Scientific Research (AFOSR)., 1961-1970; 2 folders (Box 157)
- Formatting in queues., 1969; 1979-1982 (Box 157)
- Goffman, Erving., 1952-1954 (Box 157)
  Includes 1954 March unpublished typed Goffman manuscript, "The Management of Impressions in Social Establishments."
- Gurwitsch, Aron. Theory of the field of consciousness., 1957-1958; 5 folders (Box 157)
  Includes handwritten translation from French by Arturo Biblarz (1958 Fall): "Theorie du Champ de la Conscience" (1957).
- Mike Mend and Harold Garfinkel coding procedures., 1960; 2 folders (Box 157)
- Petty, Don., 1977 January; 1 folder (Box 157)
  Transcript with Garfinkel and S. Burns.
- Provo., 1967 May/June (Box 157)
- Publications, speeches, presentations., 1989-1990; 3 folders (Box 157)
- Sketch argument tying E-intractable problems to the possibility of radicalizing science pedagogy..., 1983 (Box 157)
- Sociology 143., 1978 Spring Qtr. (Box 157)
  Wearing inverted lenses student class exercise.
- Sociology 148., 1978 Spring Qtr. (Box 157)
  Analysis of classroom blackboard notes student class exercise; includes black/white photographic prints of blackboards.
- Sociology 148., 1978 Spring Qtr. (Box 157)
  Ringing telephones student class exercise.
- Sociology 149., 1987 March; 11 folders (Box 157)
  Includes photographic snapshots of UCLA campus, Westwood, and West Los Angeles; photographs taken by UCLA students for class projects on 'Icons' and 'Queues.'
- Sociology 218 A and B., 1979-1980 (Box 157)
  Ken Lieberman's typed class notes.
- Sociology 251. Seminar: Sciences of Practical Action., 1984 Fall Qtr.; 1985 Winter Qtr.; 3 folders (Box 157)
  Edited transcripts.
- Structural strain. (Box 157)
  Includes discussion by Talcott Parsons of study by Marjorie Fiske, "Book Selection and Retention in California Public School Libraries" (no date).
- Teaching math theorem proving in geometry., 1983 (Box 157)
- Neuropsychiatric Institute (NPI). Cohort study code sheets. closed cases, 1958-1960., circa 1961 (Box 158)
- Neuropsychiatric Institute (NPI) study. Patient information. (Box 158)
  SEALED - contains information identifying patient names.
- Pat, Mike Mend, and Harold Garfinkel., circa 1961; 1 folder (Box 158)
  Transcript about the UCLA Neuropsychiatric Institute (NPI) research methodology: coding, reliability, intake interview, psychological testing.
- H.G. article, 1990; 1 folder (Box 158)
- Understanding language use in everyday life. University of Calgary conference., 1989 (Box 158)
- Neuropsychiatric Institute NPI, n.d.; 1 folder (Box 158)
- R at work 2A and B, 1 folder (Box 158)
- Boston lectures and seminars., 1975 June, July; 2 folders (Box 159)
  Photocopies of transcriptions by Richard Van de Water.
- Correspondence., 1993-2007; 3 folders (Box 159)
- Crabtree, Andy. correspondence., 2002-2003 (Box 159)
- Ethnomethodology and Conversation Analysis Section (American Sociological Association)., 1993, 2006-2007 (Box 159)
  Includes issues of the newsletter published by Paul ten Have.
- Hybrid studies publication proposal., 1998-1999 (Box 159)
  Proposal based on August 1998 American Sociological Association conference presentation, "Ethnomethodology: hybrid studies of the work place and technology." Includes email and papers.
- Notes, lists by H.G., n.d. (Box 159)
- Pubs not by H.G., 1974-1998; 3 folders (Box 159)
- Publications, speeches, presentations., 1977; 1985; 1989; 1994-2004; 29 folders (Box 159)
- Questions and answers about Ethnomethodology. Candidates for Ph.D. in Sociology., circa 1978 (Box 159)
  Photocopies with Garfinkel's annotations.
- Soc. 271 Ethnomethodology (1998 Spring Quarter), 1 folder (Box 159)
- Work practices and technology group., 1998 February 26; 1 folder (Box 159)
  Transcription.
- UCLA classroom chalk boards, c.1969 (Box 159)
  Scope and Content
  Photos of board notes.
- Agre, Phil., 1998-1999 (Box 160)
  Emails, papers re: Hybrid Studies proposal.
- Correspondence., 1998-2005 (Box 160)
- Enquete., 1998-1999 (Box 160)
  French translation and publication of H.G. article "Central claims of ethnomethodology...working out Durkheim's aphorisms."
- Fele, Giolo., 2005 (Box 160)
- Hybrid studies publication proposal., 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box 160)
- Morrison, Ken. "The disavowal of the social in the American reception of Durkeim.", 2000-2001 (Box 160)
  Copy of Morrison's article annotated by H.G.
- Orr, Julian., 1998-1999 (Box 160)
- Publications, speeches, presentations., 1987, 2001, 2004; 2 folders (Box 160)
- Wieder, D. Lawrence., 1996; 1998; 2005 (Box 160)